Alex Zuniga

Santa Cruz, CA 95060
Phone: 6267108860 | Email: alezunig@ucsc.edu
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexzuniga1998/

Summary

Bright UX researcher and designer with a BS in Cognitive Science with an emphasis in Human Computer Interaction and finishing a certificate in UX/UI from the University of California, Berkeley. Optimistic student with a passion and empathy for products and web interfaces working towards helping the environment and spreading mental health awareness. Strengths in executing projects from an idea all the way to the final project, great teamwork and communication, as well as a commitment to organization and attention to detail. Able to empathize with the user and work towards their needs, define and bring to life ideas based on user insights, wireframe and prototype lo fi to hi fi mockups, and design and code a project to full fruition.

Technical Skills

Proto Personas | User Personas | Affinity Diagramming | Empathy Mapping | User Interviews | User Insights | Prioritization Matrix | Problem Statements | Value Propositions | User Scenarios | Storyboarding | Journey Mapping | Competitive Analysis | Task Flows | User Flows | Paper Wireframing | Lo/Mid/Hi Fi Wireframing | Lo/Mid/Hi Fi Prototyping | Usability Testing | Guerrilla Testing | Interaction Design | UI Grids | UI Patterns | Typography | Color Theory | Usability Heuristics | Accessibility | Site Mapping | Information Architecture | UI Navigation | Interaction Design | Micro Interactions | Responsive Web Design | Style Tiles | Style Guides | Atomic Design | A/B Testing | Google Suite | Canva | Miro | Figma | Adobe XD | InVision | HTML | CSS | JavaScript | jQuery | Bootstrap | GitHub | Data Analysis | SPSS

Projects

NPO Responsive Web Redesign | Link to Project

- Redesigned The Marine Mammal Center NPO website in order to properly follow responsive web design protocol. Conducted a full research and interaction design plan with multiple interviews and usability tests to ultimately create a final hi fi mock up and full UI style guide, which was shared with The Marine Mammal Center and is currently under review for revision.
- Roles: UX Researcher, UX Designer, UI Designer
- Tools: Google Suite, Miro, Figma, InVision, Adobe XD

Government Website Redesign | Link to Project

- Redesigned the National Park Services government website in order to improve usability, update UI patterns, and accommodate for the limiting factors that parks offered during the COVID-19 pandemic.
 Consisted of a full research plan and was focused on UI navigation updates and the final user flow of the website.
- Roles: UX Researcher, UX Designer, UI Designer
- Tools: Google Suite, Miro, Figma, Adobe XD

Mobile Lifestyle Medicine App Case Study | Link to Project

- Designed a lifestyle medicine app called "Localist" in order to give our users an opportunity to keep up with their nutritional and physical health amidst a pandemic. Consisted of a full research plan and was focused primarily on UX and interaction design of the app.
- Roles: UX Researcher, UX Designer
- Tools: Miro, Google Suite, Figma, InVision, Adobe XD, Canva

Experience

Human Computer Interaction Research Assistant: 2020 - Current **University of California, Santa Cruz**

Creating and conducting user personas, heuristic analysis, usability test plans, and competitive analysis
of mental health app recommender sites in an effort to build and design our own, unique app
recommender service on the basis of the benefits and negatives as garnered during our review
analysis. Operating Figma and Miro canvases to brainstorm, collaborate, prototype, and involve
stakeholders in the development and interaction design process of user flow and user interface of our
mental health app recommender site.

Human Computer Interaction Research Assistant: 2019 - 2020 **University of California, Santa Cruz**

- Performed expert authentication and review analysis on 40,000+ reviews across 45 mental health apps on the Google Play Store to understand the benefits and negatives of each app expressed in user reviews. Developed a database containing app reviews and features, qualitative codebooks, academic articles, UCSC IRB protocols, and more.
- Paper under review

Education

UX/UI Bootcamp Certificate: 2020 - 2021 **University of California, Berkeley**

• Intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to UX/UI research and design. Skills learned consist of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, User-Centric Design Research, Interaction Design, Visual Prototyping & Wire framing, User Interface Development.

BS, Cognitive Science: 2016 - 2020 University of California, Santa Cruz

- Emphasis in Human Computer Interaction
- Honors in the Major